# JAMES N. SHEPPARD

(609) 618-9189 James.N.Sheppard@gmail.com

Highly-motivated IT professional with 5+ years of electronics repair and technology-related experience, and 10+ years of customer service experience. Skills include excellent communication and multi-tasking skills, comprehensive knowledge of computers, networking equipment, and small electronics, and a keen eye for analyzing problems and providing solutions.

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Bachelor of Science, Information Technology

Georgia Southern University, Statesboro, GA August 2017 - Present

Associate of Science, General Studies, Business

Ocean County College, Toms River, NJ September 2007 - December 2010

#### Certifications

Microsoft: Microsoft Windows OS Fundamentals, Windows Server Administration Fundamentals
 CIW: Web Foundations Associate, Web Design Specialist

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Computer Technician

Ewing Township Public Schools

August 2018 - Present

Ewing, NJ

- Oversee and manage daily IT operations for three school buildings with 1800 users
- Provide high-quality troubleshooting and repair of a variety of devices, including Chromebooks, Windows/Mac PCs, Smart Boards, printers, projectors, and other various hardware/software
- Work with vendors to acquire new products in an efficient and cost-effective manner
- Train a wide variety of end users, including administrators, teachers, and students on the latest technologies
- Imaging of desktops/laptops with KACE system management applications
- Active Directory administration, including group policy changes, adding/removing users, and password resets
- Implementation of network equipment such as switches and wireless access points, along with repair of TCP/IP issues

**IT Support Specialist** 

Akumin

February 2018 - August 2018

Philadelphia, PA

- Provide an efficient response to a wide variety of IT issues over a multi-location territory, ranging from southern DE to northern PA
- Remote support and troubleshooting using RDP, VNC, and TeamViewer software
- · Active Directory administration, including group policy changes, adding/removing users, and password resets
- Administration of eRAD RIS & eRAD PACS radiology systems, including account creation, workflows, and general troubleshooting.
- Work with Radiologists and Technicians to merge and split studies, as well as to make corrections to study information to ensure proper flow between PACS and RIS
- Configure DICOM network settings in multiple types of diagnostic imaging equipment, including MRI, XRay, and Ultrasound modalities

#### Technology Technician

Barnegat Township School District

January 2017 - February 2018

Barnegat, NJ

- Oversee and manage daily IT operations for two school buildings with 1300 users
- Manage users and devices through both Google's administrative console and Active Directory
- Provide high-quality troubleshooting and repair of a variety of devices, including Chromebooks, Windows/Mac PCs, Smart Boards, printers, projectors, and other various hardware/software
- Train a wide variety of end users, including administrators, teachers, and students on the latest technologies

## Computer Technician

March 2016 - January 2017

Oakhurst, NJ

Ocean Township School District

- Oversee and manage daily IT operations for one school building with 1400 users
- Provide high-quality troubleshooting and repair of a variety of devices, including Windows/Mac PCs, document cameras, Smart Boards, projectors, printers, and other various hardware/software
- Work with Active Directory tools to assist with end user account requests
- Install network and POTS cabling, along with indoor and outdoor CCTV cameras, and repair any accidental damage and resolve any software issues

#### Technical Consultant

May 2011 - March 2016

Toms River, NJ

Sprint Nextel Corporation

- Provide quick and efficient in-house support to customers on operational and maintenance issues of equipment
- Diagnose mechanical, hardware/software, and systems failures using established procedures and a variety of tools, and disassemble, assemble, and replace parts as needed
- Serve as a customer contact for service-related problems and follow-up with customers to ensure equipment is still functional